<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Projects on Antoine Vugliano </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
    
    <updated>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>Collimateru</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/collimateru/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/collimateru/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This project is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Path_tracing&#34;&gt;path tracer&lt;/a&gt; running on CPU, for educational purpose.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development is on-going, it currently features:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Global Illumination&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Point and sphere lights&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Diffuse, specular, refractive, glossy materials&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Multi-material surfaces&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/collimateru-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Skeletons</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/skeletons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/skeletons/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Skeletons&lt;/strong&gt; is a procedural generator of animalish skeletons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;During my year at &lt;a href=&#34;/tags/Gamagora&#34;&gt;Gamagora&lt;/a&gt;, I attended a short course on procedural generation. As a final project, I wrote this generator with two friends.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Objectives&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I thought, probably influenced by the game &lt;em&gt;Spore&lt;/em&gt;, that generating creatures would be interesting; and it&amp;rsquo;s quite different from the sempiternal terrains.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Generating a complete creature with bones, organs, tissues would require an incredible amount of work though, so we limited ourselves to skeletons. This is afterall what gives its structure to a body, and we can use our imagination to build the rest. Doing so also has the advantage that we could easily translate it to 3D animation skeletons afterwards.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Accessibility&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Procedural generation is a pretty &lt;em&gt;cool&lt;/em&gt; subject in computer science, and lots of programmers enjoy doing things that work, but that are comprehensible only to other programmers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In the video games world, procedural generation is used to produce large quantities of various content, but it is easy to forget that somebody has to do a quality check on the generated content. This person is most probably a non-tech, like an artist or level designer. The other goal of creating a procedural generator is therefore to make it usable by other people, who do not necessarily understand how it works.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Technical side&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Engine&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The engine for this generator is a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/L-system&#34;&gt;L-system&lt;/a&gt; library we wrote during course, and improved for this project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Our skeletons are defined by a grammar, consisting of rules that describe how bones are produced. Given a starting point; the &lt;em&gt;axiom&lt;/em&gt;, the engine will process the rules to expand our axiom into a list of &lt;em&gt;symbols&lt;/em&gt; to which we give meaning: these will be our bones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;Sample grammar&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code&gt;Trunk → Head Spine Tail
Spine → HighSpine LowSpine
HighSpine → Vertebra [Arm] Vertebra HighSpine
HighSpine → ε
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These rules are translated into Python code, but in the current state they do not provide enough information to produce interesting skeletons. That&amp;rsquo;s why we introduced parameters into our rules, to have more complex emerging behaviors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_6&#34;&gt;UI&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The symbols are then processed by a set of &lt;em&gt;drawing commands&lt;/em&gt;: they abstract the way to represent symbols. It could be anything like printing their names to the console, or sending meshes to a 3D printer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to have visual and real-time feedback for the user, so having a 3D view of our skeletons inside the project was the goal. This way, we could also put parameters as widgets inside the UI and let the user play with the generator at its full extent.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_7&#34;&gt;Result&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/skeletons-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cosse toi d&#39;là !</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/cosse%20toi%20d%27l%C3%A0%20%21/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/cosse%20toi%20d%27l%C3%A0%20%21/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;Only two days after the &lt;a href=&#34;/projects/dalicious&#34;&gt;MIG&lt;/a&gt;, I took part in the &lt;a href=&#34;http://gamedevparty.fr&#34;&gt;Game Dev Party #7&lt;/a&gt;, a game jam organized in lyon two times a year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The theme was, in French: &amp;ldquo;Petit pois, gros poi(ds)&amp;rdquo;. This is a pun over the fact that &lt;em&gt;pois&lt;/em&gt; (pea) and &lt;em&gt;poids&lt;/em&gt; (weight) are pronounced the same way.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The GDP is a very friendly game jam, there is no competition between teams. The organizers also promote taking some sleep during the jam. As a result, the office hosting it is closed from midnight to 8am. The event lasts then less than 48 hours.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Peass off!&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My team was composed of 4 members: one game designer, one graphist and two developers including me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We wanted to develop a simple game that we could potentially make playable by the end of the jam; to avoid going for a too big project.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The concept of the game is very simple: you are a pea among four that are struggling to keep their place in the plate. The edges of the plate are elevated, so that the slope and gravity attract the peas towards the center.
To eject other peas, you have to charge a impulsion and release it in direction of an opponent, inertia will do the rest. Each player has a jauge driving this charge, so beware of not wasting it because it has to refill!
Sometimes small zones will pop that modify the friction of your pea, they can slow you or give acceleration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game is playable up to four players with XBOX 360 controllers. We used the lua framework &lt;strong&gt;LÖVE&lt;/strong&gt; with a homemade entity component framework.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cosse-01.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cosse-02.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/cosse-03.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dalicious</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/dalicious/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Nov 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/dalicious/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In november 2014, I registered for the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.montpellieringame.com/index.php/events/game-challenge/&#34;&gt;Game Challenge&lt;/a&gt;, taking place during the Montpellier In Game summit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Teams of around 10 students were formed with developers, graphists, game designers and sound artists. Each group had to draw five random constraints for their game. We picked the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a camera as input for the game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use a 2D axis input for something else than moving a camera or an object in-game&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a cooking mechanic as core gameplay&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Take inspiration from Dali&amp;rsquo;s work for the game art&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Have a dynamic soundtrack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Not an easy task.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We still managed to have a working prototype at the end of the three days.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SHMµP</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/shmup/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Aug 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/shmup/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;SHMµP&lt;/strong&gt; is a little game I work on during my spare time. I felt like it reached the point where I can show it, so here we go. It is by no means finished, but more like a demo at the current state; yet it is totally playable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/shmup-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;screenshot&#34; /&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;http://i.imgur.com/ZhXGJkz.png&#34; alt=&#34;color blocks image&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;What is this game about ?&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;Minimalism&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Going for graphic minimalism is certainly an easy way to avoid doing art. My art skills being non-existent, it allowed me to have a very small amount of assets (basically a single 64*8 texture) in the game, and to give it a coherent look and feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;block&lt;/strong&gt; is the elementary unit in the game. The player&amp;rsquo;s ship, enemies, bullets, everything is composed of blocks.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Blocks are important for the gameplay, of course. They are what you will use to build your ship, making it unique. Each block has a particular effect on your ship, and so the do on enemies!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;https://i.imgflip.com/f00j2.jpg&#34; alt=&#34;blocks everywhere&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Yet no mining, no crafting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_2&#34;&gt;Procedural content&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I am lazy, so this game includes 0 stages.
The good news is, no stage means infinite stage: the enemies are generated on the fly, by a clever algorithm (soon™).
As time passes, the difficulty increases. By beating enemies, getting bonus and avoiding getting hit, the player increases his skill-o-meter. Waves will then adapt the way they generate enemies based on these 2 parameters, among others.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game relies heavily on random, but every run can be replayed: you just need to enter the same seed once again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_3&#34;&gt;Scripting&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Enemies are scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Waves are scripts.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Scripts are simple &lt;em&gt;lua&lt;/em&gt; files one can drop in the scripts folder and they will just work. They use a very simple &lt;em&gt;API&lt;/em&gt;, making it easy for anybody with basic programming knowledge to write one.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;toc_4&#34;&gt;Sample enemy script&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&#34;language-lua&#34;&gt;BLOCKS = {
    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None,
    blocks.None,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.None,
    blocks.None,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.None,
    blocks.None,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.Blue,    blocks.None,
    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None,    blocks.None
}

local onScreen = false
local start

function init(enemy)
    enemy:setMaxLife(1)
    enemy:setLife(1)
end

function update(enemy)
    if not onScreen then
        start = game.time
        onScreen = true
    end
    local duration = game.time:since(start):asSeconds()
    enemy:setSpeedY(math.cos(2*duration)*60)
end
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_5&#34;&gt;External links&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;http://sahnvour.github.io/SHMµP/&#34;&gt;Download&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://github.com/Sahnvour/shmup-scripting&#34;&gt;Scripting documentation&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Lego Mindstorm</title>
      <link>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/holidayz/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2014 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      <author>Antoine Vugliano</author>
      <guid>http://sahnvour.github.io/projects/holidayz/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;As an optional project using &lt;em&gt;innovative technologies&lt;/em&gt;, we (a group of 7 students) created a robot with the following objectives:
- grab and store small plastic balls
- differentiate blue and red balls
- find its way in an environment with obstacles&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h1 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;Setup&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The robot was built with a &lt;a href=&#34;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lego_Mindstorms_EV3&#34;&gt;Mindstorm&lt;/a&gt; brick to control the different motors (wheels, arms).
We put a smartphone on it, filming the ground just in front of it to detect balls and move accordingly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/holidayz-01.png&#34; alt=&#34;robot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The play field was filmed by 4 cameras with different view angles, streaming their videos on the local network. A computer ran our server program that constructed a single view of the field from the cameras, and identified balls and obstacles before sending them to the robot. It also analysed video streamed from the smartphone to detect near-by balls. The software on the Lego brick was then able to compute its moves to catch the balls and find its way to an arbitrary point using the info from the server.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;/img/holidayz-02.png&#34; alt=&#34;robot&#34; /&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>